artfulparent.com 2019-06-01

# Disclosure and Privacy Policy

## Disclosure and Privacy Policy

####  _Effective May 29, 2018_

Hi. I’m Jean Van’t Hul, the owner of The Artful Parent. I understand that your privacy is of critical importance. This Privacy Policy describes what information is collected from you at The Artful Parent and how that information is used and disclosed.

## Who we are

The Artful Parent website address is: [https://artfulparent.com](https://artfulparent.com/)

## Disclosure Statement

The Artful Parent blog is owned by Artful Media LLC.

The Artful Parent blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation.

The compensation received may occasionally influence the content selected to publish and the timing of that post. That content, advertising space or post will be identified as such within the guidelines of the FTC disclosure rules.

The views and opinions expressed on The Artful Parent are purely those of me, Jean Van’t Hul, chief blogger and children’s art enabler. Even though The Artful Parent blog receives compensation for some posts and advertisements, I always give my honest opinion, findings, beliefs, and experiences on those topics or products. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

I only work with companies and organizations I believe in and share products that I love and think that you will love, too.

If you have any questions, please feel free to e-mail The Artful Parent team at hello@artfulparent.com

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The [Gravatar service privacy policy is available here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### IP Address

Our web service may automatically collect the standard details of your browser and operating system, the website from which you visit our website, the pages that you browse on our website, and the date of your visit. For security reasons (to identify attacks on our website) the Internet protocol (IP) address that is assigned to you by your internet service is also collected when you load The Artful Parent site.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

At The Artful Parent, we also use cookies to help us display advertisements that will be relevant to you and to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including The Artful Parent. Some features of the The Artful Parent may cease to be available to you.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. [Google’s privacy policy is available here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.) Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

##  **Interest-Based Advertising**

### Advertising Privacy Statement

The Artful Parent is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using The Artful Parent, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners.You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

### For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

## Who we share your data with

### Email

We only collect your email if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter or opt-in to a free printable or e-course.  We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the The Artful Parent.  You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button on the bottom of every email.

We collect this data through two separate platforms, LeadPages and ConvertKit. You can read the [LeadPages privacy policy here](https://www.leadpages.net/privacy) (applicable section is under “Customer Data”) and the [ConvertKit privacy policy here](https://www.leadpages.net/privacy) (section 6).

We will not share your email address with any third parties.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

 **Registration or Account Data**

We may collect other information from you when you register with our Site in order to use various features.  Such information could include your name and email address.

We may use third parties to provide the functionality to allow you to register for the Site, in which case the third party will also have access to your information. Otherwise, we will not provide any personally-identifying information about you to third parties, except if required by law.

We may use your personally-identifying information for a variety of our internal business purposes, such as creating a better user experience for The Artful Parent, diagnosing and troubleshooting malfunctions on The Artful Parent, better understanding how The Artful Parent is used, and making personalized recommendations to you.

 **Additional Rights of EEA (European Economic Area) Residents**

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i)  access your personal data

(ii)  ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv)  the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v)  the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us addressed to the following:

 **Jean Van’t Hul  
PO Box 18204  
Asheville, NC 28814  
hello@artfulparent.com**

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if you have purchased something from The Artful Parent store, for example), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Questions? Contact The Artful Parent

You can always direct any data or privacy questions to The Artful Parent team at hello@artfulparent.com

##  **Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on The Artful Parent, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the Policy. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new services or change existing ones. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy or how we handle your personal information, or we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected such information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change. If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information. By using our Site or services after the Effective Date, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy. We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained from you.
